何世紀もの間、地球上に生息する
多様な生物種を研究してきました。
それは自然の仕組みを理解するためです。
世界中の何千もの機関と人々の努力により
生み出された知識が
何百万という出版物を通して見えるようになり、
「生物多様性」のキーワードで探すことができます。
こういった情報の背景にあるデータは多くの場合、
散在していてアクセスしにくい状況です。
このデータに価値が付くのは
分析、利用、再利用に使えるときであり
知識の創造と向上のための重要な基盤となります。
想像してみてください。もっと多くの人々が
整理された状態のデータを利用できるなら
どれくらいの知識が生み出されることになるのか。
地球規模生物多様性情報機構（GBIF）は
政府および組織のネットワークであり
研究者や市民が所在に関わらず利用ができる
and shares it with the world,
making information about biodiversity
available online for researchers and citizens,
regardless of their location.
In response to recommendations
from international agreements and conventions,
GBIF includes dozens of participating countries
and nearly 2,000 publishers,
bringing together a global scale data infrastructure for the natural world
that informs the sustainable use of biodiversity
and contributes to improving people’s quality of life.
GBIF allows you to share the data that you capture,
organize, standardize and publish,
contributing to research, education and decision-making
and expanding the knowledge we have about our environment.
Data publishers can choose the type of use and attribution
that they want for their data
and receive public recognition for their contributions.
GBIF also makes it possible
for any citizen of the world, including you,
to access all the free and open data
published through the network’s data portals.
The nodes from each one of the participating countries
advise and work with organizations
through all phases of the data publishing process
to guarantee high-quality data, that are open and accessible.
We want you to be part of GBIF,
so that together we can build a sustainable future
in which biodiversity information is free and universally available
to science and society.
To learn more about how to become part of
this global biodiversity network,
visit www.gbif.org.